# **Evgenii Solovev**

Almaty, KZ | +7 (777) 524-1173 | evgenii.solovev.dev@proton.me | LinkedIn | Telegram | WhatsApp | LeetCode

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

**Senior .NET engineer** with over 10 years of working experience, specializing in backend engineering. Help companies create high-load services from scratch or enhance existing products. With a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science, work effectively in cross-functional teams, finding common ground with analysts and QAs and always willing to contribute to collective goals. Still like to research and use new technologies (even ready to consider switching professional stack). My goal is to continue my career as a software engineer in a cross-functional team that values initiative, professionalism and teamwork to create solutions that improve user experience and drive business results.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Senior Software Engineer, Tinkoff Bank

Sept 2020 - Present

- Designed and assembled high-load cloud telephony services
- Migrated mono repository solution (150+ projects) from .NET 4.7 to .NET 6: code and dependencies updates (including EF, SignalR), Oracle client's replacement (from managed to unmanaged), migration from IIS to Kestrel
- Transferred code-base and CI\CD pipelines from TeamCity and Bitbucket to Gitlab
- Participated in division of mono repository to separated repos: designed services interaction and data flow schemes
- Produced emergency mechanism in TypeScript telephony client, which can detect backend failure and run light-weight
  version of itself, that could provide basic operation without using backend (also detecting backend recovery for
  returning to normal state)
- Created new scheme for widget-widget interaction that used WebRTC with STUN\TURN services instead of historically established heavy pattern (TS client => REST-backend => RabbitMq => SignalR => another client)
- Engaged in third-line supporting and production duty

### Senior Software Engineer, **Beeline Russia**

Jan 2018 - Aug 2020

- Improved performance and implemented features for the main B2C site
- Revamped the existing Lucene-based search index service
- Renovated authorization service originally developed by contractors
- Involved in third-line supporting

## Middle Software Engineer, SimbirSoft

Apr 2017 - Dec 2017

- Built internal team tools
- Implemented features and fixed bugs in several projects
- Improved Lucene-based search index application

### Junior Software Engineer, PROMO IT

Oct 2014 - Mar 2017

- Created and edited 20+ e-commerce solutions based on AdvantShop platform
- Built 10+ custom extension modules to AdvantShop platform (mostly integrations with goods suppliers), that have been sold on internal shop

### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION**

### **Microsoft Certified Professional**

2017 - 2019

• Credential ID G405-7161

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science, <u>Ulyanovsk State Technology University</u>

2011 - 2015

### **SKILLS**

- Languages: C# (proficiency in ASP.NET), TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- Data: SQL (PostgreSQL, Oracle, SQL Server), RabbitMQ, Kafka, Redis
- **DevOps:** GitLab CI/CD, TeamCity, Octopus
- Software: Rider, Git, Jira, Confluence, Kibana, Grafana, Prometheus, Consul, Vault, S3, ZooKeeper